<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Doswah</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="" />
<updated>2015-03-18T21:51:02-10:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>Joshua T. Rivera</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>doswah@gmail.com</email>
</author>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chasing Luck]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/chasing-luck/" />
  <id>/chasing-luck</id>
  <published>2015-03-09T00:00:00-10:00</published>
  <updated>2015-03-09T00:00:00-10:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Joshua T. Rivera</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>doswah@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am an huge fan of NBC’s Parks and Recreation and one my favorite episodes are when Ben and his friends each do something they have always wanted to do for their bachelor’s party (but didn’t have an opportunity to). Andy told his friends his impossible dream is to “catch a touchdown in the Super Bowl and watch the Colts beat the Patriots 49-nothing”. Then the spectacular happened:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;340&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/y4KIm9y6Rss&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This weekend, a variety of celebrities for a USO Tour to show their appreciation for the U.S. Armed Services. The list of celebrities included Andrew Luck, Chuck Pagano, and Dwayne Allen of the Indianapolis Colts.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The USO Tour made a stop at Pearl Harbor so &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/jaketsuyemura&quot;&gt;Jake&lt;/a&gt; had a great idea to check out the event and enjoy the festivities. Jake is a huge Colts fan, it would be a great opportunity to meet the Colts players and their Head Coach. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/chasing-luck/uso-tour.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a huge stage setup and various food vendors making it a great event for families. I forgot my football in car, when I went I came back, Andrew Luck was meeting and autographing for fans. The only thing I had was a football I would throw around with friends when I went to UH and ironically it was deflated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/chasing-luck/luck-1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Giving my ball the &quot;Andrew Luck 12&quot; treatment.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few minutes of waiting, I got chance to meet Mr. Luck, thank him for his contribution with this Tour and everything he has done for the Colts organization. It was tremendous. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/chasing-luck/luck-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No such thing as an impossible dream.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/chasing-luck/&quot;&gt;Chasing Luck&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Joshua T. Rivera at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Doswah&lt;/a&gt; on March 09, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[What Is Trumps?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/coding/assembling-an-online-trumps-game/" />
  <id>/coding/assembling-an-online-trumps-game</id>
  <updated>2014-11-09 17:08:28 -1000T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2014-11-09T00:00:00-10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Joshua T. Rivera</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>doswah@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Starting in my high school days and going through my college years, I played a card game 
so invigorating where cleverness and wit are needed to stand
victorious at the end. No, not &lt;em&gt;Magic: The Gathering&lt;/em&gt;. I’m talking about &lt;strong&gt;Trumps&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Creating an online trumps game would allow my
college buddies and I to play the game we spent hours playing in between homework breaks.
Back then, we played to get away from the work. If this game came to fruition, it can
become a way for people to come together, no matter where they are in the world (as long
as they have Wi-Fi).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-setup--pre-game&quot;&gt;The Setup / Pre-Game&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To picture what a trumps game would look like, this post is  to lay down the basis of the game’s
rules and flowchart to clarify any inconsistencies (since the game has spawned unique 
rules over the years).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/trumps/trumps-deal.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Typical deal setup for Trumps&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game consists of a 4-player, 2 vs. 2 system. In the figure above, Hands &lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt; are 
teammates and vice-versa, Hands &lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt; are teammates. With 52 cards in a deck, each lettered
player is dealt 12 cards and 4 cards are placed at the center of the table called the &lt;em&gt;Kit&lt;/em&gt; 
(12+12+12+12+4=52).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bidding-war&quot;&gt;Bidding War&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the hands are dealt, &lt;em&gt;the player &lt;strong&gt;left&lt;/strong&gt; of the dealer makes a “bid” to 1) win the kit 
2) declare what suit trumps is and 3) Designate how many packs the other team must make to win&lt;/em&gt;. 
Each player has the chance to bid with the dealer getting to bid last. A player can overbid 
the previous bid by bidding a higher number. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In accordance to the bidding number, each bid is either &lt;strong&gt;LOW&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;HIGH&lt;/strong&gt;. A &lt;strong&gt;LOW&lt;/strong&gt; bid declares 
lower valued cards in a suit are stronger in the game, while vice-versa, a &lt;strong&gt;HIGH&lt;/strong&gt; bid declares 
higher valued cards in a suit are stronger. In all games, the ACE card 
is the strongest card of the suit. In the following table, the higher the card is in the table, 
the stronger it is during the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;When LOW bid wins&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;When HIGH bid wins&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;ACE&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;ACE&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;KING&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;QUEEN&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;JACK&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
     &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’s important to note: a LOW bid over-rules a HIGH bid.&lt;/em&gt; For example, consider Player A starts 
the bidding at &lt;em&gt;4 HIGH&lt;/em&gt;. If the following player bids &lt;em&gt;4 LOW&lt;/em&gt;, then
he or she now holds the current winning bid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned earlier, the winning bid determines how much packs the other 
team needs to make to win the game. Here is what each bidding number represents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Packs&lt;/strong&gt; are considered as a round where all four players contribute a card in play. Since 
each player has 12-cards, there are 12 rounds or “packs”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table rules=&quot;groups&quot;&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Winning Bid&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;# of Packs Other Team Needs To Win&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;5&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Once a player wins the bid he or she uses the “Kit” to add/remove cards to improve their 
12-card hand. Once that’s done, the player declares what “trumps” is and then the game
begins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-trumps-works&quot;&gt;How Trumps Works&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I explained the quite troublesome setup for a trumps game, but now we to get into the fun. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Each round, a player adds one card to the pile and person who adds the strongest card wins a 
pack for their team. When a person wins a pack for their team, they become the person 
who throws first for the next round. Now introducing trumps. “Trumps” represent the &lt;strong&gt;suit&lt;/strong&gt; that 
overpowers cards from the other three suits. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In a game, the player who throws first declares the suit “in play”. Each player must throw 
the suit in play. When a person does not have the suit in play, they can 
throw a trump, to better their chances to win the pack. According to the rules, the trump suit cannot 
be used to start a round unless previous scenario occurs (due to lack of “in play” suit in someone’s hand). This is commonly referred to as “Breaking Trumps”.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Those are the basic rules of Trumps. Let’s examine a few rounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-example-game-of-trumps&quot;&gt;An Example Game of Trumps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The great Christian Damo (&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/HenryHanakahi&quot;&gt;@HenryHanakahi&lt;/a&gt;) taught me 
that introducing a scenario is a productive way to explain people new things. So let’s consider
this scenario.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Players A &amp;amp; C are a team (so, players B &amp;amp; D are a team).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Player C wins the bid at &lt;strong&gt;4 LOW&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Player C declares trumps as &lt;strong&gt;SPADES&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Images for card faces in the following scenarios are provided by &lt;a href=&quot;http://was.fm/assets:textures:playing_cards&quot;&gt;was.fm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now since player C won the bid, he starts the game of by throwing a suit. This is what happens…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Player C throws 4 of HEARTS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Player D throws 6 of HEARTS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Player A throws 9 of HEARTS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Player B throws 2 of HEARTS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/trumps/trumps-hand-1.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Player C throws and declares HEARTS as the suit in play. Player D could not beat the 4 of HEARTS so he throws any heart, in this scenario he throws the 6 of HEARTS. 
Next Player A throws a 9 of HEARTS because heassumes the 4 of HEARTS his partner threw will win. 
Now Player B throws the 2 of HEARTS, resulting in his team winning a pack. Just a taste of how rough this game can be. Since Player B won, he will start the next round.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Player B throws 7 of DIAMONDS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Player C throws ACE of DIAMONDS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Player D throws 10 of SPADES&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Player A throws 9 of DIAMONDS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/trumps/trumps-hand-2.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Player B declares DIAMONDS as the suit in play. Player C attempts to win the hand by playing the ACE of DIAMONDS (the strongest number of a suit). It appears 
Player D does not have any DIAMONDS in his hand so Player D is entitled to throw a “trump” card. 
Like I mentioned earlier, the trumps suit overpowers any of the other three suits. So although 
Player C threw an ACE, Player D’s 10 of SPADES is stronger since it is a “trump”. Unfortunately for 
Player A, he cannot throw a trump to beat Player D’s 10 of SPADES because he or she still has DIAMONDS. 
As a reminder since the first player, Player B, started out with a DIAMOND, everyone must throw a 
DIAMOND unless they don’t have any.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been a basic introduction into how the game of trumps works. Next post I plan introduce 
how to organize a card deck in a coding viewpoint using classes. Also I will discuss the language and 
technology stack I could use for the game. I am at an early stage and have a lot to plan and 
research. Until next time.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/coding/assembling-an-online-trumps-game/&quot;&gt;What Is Trumps?&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Joshua T. Rivera at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Doswah&lt;/a&gt; on November 09, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ed Sheeran: The one-man act]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/ed-sheeran-live/" />
  <id>/ed-sheeran-live</id>
  <updated>2014-09-01 18:31:46 -1000T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2014-09-01T00:00:00-10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Joshua T. Rivera</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>doswah@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ed-sheeran/concert-3.JPG&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Las Vegas. The Chelsea at The Cosmopolitan in Las Vegas. A stop on Ed Sheeran’s &lt;em&gt;Multiply&lt;/em&gt; tour. 
Rudimental opened up performing hits: &lt;em&gt;Free&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Waiting All Night&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Feel The Love&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Not Giving In&lt;/em&gt;. 
Definitely check these guys out, they were loud, upbeat, and knew how to party.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 
The chants grew… “Ed! Ed! Ed!” He walks out with a grin and says… 
“Hey, I’m Ed. My job is to entertain you for the next two hours. It’s your job to 
be entertained. Well… for the next two hours.” 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
An Ed Sheeran show is simple. No dancers, no background singers, no band, but instead, two microphones, 
a loop pedal, and his guitar. His setlist composed of his hits first two albums, &lt;em&gt;+&lt;/em&gt; (Plus) and &lt;em&gt;x&lt;/em&gt; (Multiply).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ed-sheeran/concert-2.PNG&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&quot;Thinking Out Loud&quot; goes well with a blue lightshow&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-setlist&quot;&gt;The Setlist&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m a Mess &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lego House &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drunk &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take It Back &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bloodstream &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tenerife Sea &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Runaway / Everybody (Backstreet Boys) &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thinking Out Loud &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hit Me Baby One More Time (Britney Spears) / Give Me Love &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I See Fire &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;encore&quot;&gt;Encore&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t Need Me&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The A-Team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/ed-sheeran/concert-1.PNG&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Ed climbs onto a speaker to get the crowd to sing along to &quot;A-Team&quot;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a great concert considering it was a one-man show. Loud acoustics and beat-boxing compiled 
into a great show that ranks as one of the best concerts I have been to. Lastly, here is a clip 
from the concert of “Thinking Out Loud.” Enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;340&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/USH66UfcvFE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/ed-sheeran-live/&quot;&gt;Ed Sheeran: The one-man act&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Joshua T. Rivera at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Doswah&lt;/a&gt; on September 01, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Is There Never A Big Red Button?]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/big-red-button/" />
  <id>/big-red-button</id>
  <updated>2014-08-24 19:58:26 -1000T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2014-08-24T00:00:00-10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Joshua T. Rivera</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>doswah@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We all want the obvious answer. 
When faced with a decision, we want that big red button because we all like
to emphasize the moment we come to a decision. There’s just something sexy about it. 
It’s simplicity and boldness makes deciding much easier (even for Time Lords).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Button/doctor-who.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Doctor Who&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-photobooth-trigger&quot;&gt;A Photobooth Trigger&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An application of such a button is to take pictures with a photobooth. 
You’re about to take an epic selfie with your friends, so why not?
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The idea is to use a button paired with an &lt;a href=&quot;http://arduino.cc/en/Main/ArduinoBoardMicro&quot;&gt;Arduino Micro&lt;/a&gt; 
to emulate a mouse click to start a Photobooth application. The Micro is the perfect microprocessor because of it’s size and the built-in USB communication. So after ordering a 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.karlssonrobotics.com/cart/big-dome-push-button-red/&quot;&gt;dome button from Karlsson Robotics&lt;/a&gt;
I began programming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/Button/button.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By using the Karlsson Robotics &lt;a href=&quot;http://play.karlssonrobotics.com/tutorials/circuits/wire-big-dome-button/&quot;&gt;tutorial&lt;/a&gt;, 
I understood the reasoning behind a normally open (NO) or normally closed (NC) switch. 
In terms of digital logic, a NO switches from a 0 to 1 and a NC switches from a 1 to 0.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Since we are essentially powering an LED, the Arduino operating voltage (5V) is sufficent 
to power the button as well. Initializing the mouse button functionality is as simple as
adding this to the setup function:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;pinMode(mouseButton, INPUT);
Mouse.begin();&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After connecting the NO pin to a digital input on the Arduino Micro, I setup the Arduino so 
whenever the big red button is pressed, I can emulate a particular mouse click. I triggered a mouse left-click by adding:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;if (clickState == HIGH) {
    Mouse.press(MOUSE_LEFT); 
}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s as simple as that. Even the doctor himself thinks it’s cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;http://28.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_lofhnlEdGv1qmm6ylo1_500.gif&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Doctor Who&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process is pretty straight-forward. There are a lot of USB functions you could set up such as 
mouse movement or triggering keyboard keys. The possibilites are only limited to your imagination!  I’ll post a circuit schematic and video soon.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/big-red-button/&quot;&gt;Why Is There Never A Big Red Button?&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Joshua T. Rivera at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Doswah&lt;/a&gt; on August 24, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Take: Webpage PHP Modules]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/first-take-website-php-modules/" />
  <id>/first-take-website-php-modules</id>
  <updated>2014-08-09 00:31:48 -1000T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2014-08-09T00:00:00-10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Joshua T. Rivera</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>doswah@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After a few months of developing my web development skills, I slowly realized
how messy and intricate webpage files can get. This fueled to my desire toward 
finding cool ways to manage a webpage’s organization.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Now each webpage consists of multiple modules such as the navigation bar, header wraps, various content, and 
the footer: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/website_organization.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I discovered from a &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.kennyluong.com/php/&quot;&gt;blog post by Kenny Luong&lt;/a&gt; that creating 
PHP modules allows pages to utilize modules that have one dependency. 
I use this method on my personal site &lt;a href=&quot;http&amp;quot;//joshuatrivera.com&quot;&gt;joshuatrivera.com&lt;/a&gt;
by converting pages from .html to .php
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt; 
Here is a snippet of my &lt;em&gt;cumbersome&lt;/em&gt; navigation bar at the beginning of all my pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;navbar navbar-default navbar-fixed-top&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;role=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;navigation&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;container&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;navbar-header&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;button&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;type=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;button&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;navbar-toggle&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;data-toggle=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;collapse&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;data-target=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;.navbar-collapse&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;span&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;sr-only&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Toggle navigation&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;span&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;icon-bar&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;span&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;icon-bar&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;span&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;icon-bar&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/button&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;navbar-brand&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;index.php&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;JTR&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;navbar-collapse collapse navbar-right&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;ul&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;nav navbar-nav&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;li&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;active&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;index.php&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;HOME&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;resume.php&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;RESUME&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    		&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;http://doswah.com&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;BLOG&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;       
            &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;li&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;dropdown&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
              &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;#&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;dropdown-toggle&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;data-toggle=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;dropdown&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;PROJECTS &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;b&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;caret&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
              &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;ul&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;class=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;dropdown-menu&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;na&quot;&gt;href=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;micromouse.php&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;MICROMOUSE&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
              &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
       &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I placed this snippet as a .php file in a folder of modules. 
Now to include the navigation bar in my index.php page, I just need to have:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-css&quot; data-lang=&quot;css&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;php&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;include&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;modules/menubar.php&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;?&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it. Pretty awesome right? This method helps my pages become modular and makes reading my webpage code easier for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remember!&lt;/strong&gt; Rename &lt;em&gt;both&lt;/em&gt; your module snippet and webpage to a .php file&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/first-take-website-php-modules/&quot;&gt;First Take: Webpage PHP Modules&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Joshua T. Rivera at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Doswah&lt;/a&gt; on August 09, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rank 'Em:  Disney Channel Original Movies]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/DCOM-rank/" />
  <id>/DCOM-rank</id>
  <updated>2014-06-25 09:33:40 -1000T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2014-06-25T00:00:00-10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Joshua T. Rivera</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>doswah@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently stumbled upon a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buzzfeed.com/jaimieetkin/the-definitive-ranking-of-disney-channel-original-movies?bffbent&quot;&gt;BuzzFeed article&lt;/a&gt; ranking all Disney Channel Original Movies. At an early age, I have been a fan of these quirky, weird, underdog characters and stories.  They are filled with self-fulfilling moments, meaningful relationships, and inspirational stories (sometimes no-brainers). Since I’m turning 24 today, I’ve compiled a list of my top 24. I haven’t watched all the DCOMs so if you think I’m missing something from this list or got it wrong, please let me know in the comments below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;now-you-see-it-2005&quot;&gt;24. Now You See It… (2005)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DCOM/24_NowYouSeeIt.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Disney Channel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Just one more puzzle begging to be solved.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A film that tackles the idea of real magic when a produce holds a competition to crown the best young magician. The aspiring illusionist Danny teams up with the upbeat Allyson to solve the true intention of the contest. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-even-stevens-movie-2003&quot;&gt;23. The Even Stevens Movie (2003)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DCOM/23_TheEvenStevensMovie.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Disney Channel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This morning, I thought I saw a cheeseburger doing yoga!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A movie from the Disney Channel show, the film is about a family stranded on an island unknowingly competing on a game show. All the characters play to their strengths and the Stevens realized what they should’ve known all along: nothing is stronger than their bond of a family.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;horse-sense-1999&quot;&gt;22. Horse Sense (1999)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DCOM/22_HorseSense.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Disney Channel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I got a four-year-old nephew who works harder than you do.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A funny and touching story about learning how to adapt to another world; whether it is the fast-paced L.A. or rugged farm life. By the confusion and hardships, you can uncover a side of yourself you never knew you had.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;go-figure-2005&quot;&gt;21. Go Figure! (2005)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DCOM/21_GoFigure.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Disney Channel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What kind of hockey player runs away from a fight?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The story about a teenage girl aspiring to become a professional ice-skater but has to play hockey to pay for a scholarship where a top instructor works. Similar to &lt;em&gt;Ice Princess&lt;/em&gt;, this film had me rooting for the main character while she discovered the other side of the ice. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stuck-in-the-suburbs-2004&quot;&gt;20. Stuck in the Suburbs (2004)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DCOM/20_StuckInTheSuburbs.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Disney Channel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can’t blame the location, you can only blame yourself. The suburbs are just a state of mind.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Before Taran Killam made it big on SNL and Wildin’ Out, he played a popstar. In this DCOM, the characters realize how power can change a person (whether gaining it or losing it) and how it can help you realize what you want to do with your life. More Brenda Song movies to come.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jumping-ship-2001&quot;&gt;19. Jumping Ship (2001)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DCOM/19_JumpingShip.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Disney Channel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Look! A Plane!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
More comedy than action, the sequel to No. 22 added a third Lawrence brother for a action packed adventure. A story of survival, I learned what to do if every I was shipwrecked on an island and pirates are trying to kidnap me (not really).
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-a-clue-2002&quot;&gt;18. Get A Clue (2002)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DCOM/18_GetAClue.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Disney Channel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is no secret, it is all about skill.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Back when Lindsay Lohan was a child star, she appeared in this film about a students from a local school paper who solve a missing teacher case. I have always been a fan of mystery stories and this movie did the trick.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;genius-1999&quot;&gt;17. Genius (1999)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DCOM/17_Genius.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Disney Channel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Well, you can’t be in two places at once. Violates all fundamental laws of physics.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A young kid with a high IQ learns the problems of living a double life. It taught kids that you should try to embrace who you are and not change just to fit in. It can turn out being yourself attracts your real friends. Oh and it’s cool to see a young Emily Rossum (&lt;em&gt;The Day After Tomorrow&lt;/em&gt;).
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-thirteenth-year-1999&quot;&gt;16. The Thirteenth Year (1999)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DCOM/16_TheThirteenthYear.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Disney Channel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I finally get a friend and he turns into a fish. Typical.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Becoming a teenager and learning that you are a mermaid. Although outrageous, it still dealt with the struggles of fitting in school and how important your friends and family are when you are having a hard time.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-ultimate-christmas-present-2000&quot;&gt;15. The Ultimate Christmas Present (2000)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DCOM/15_TheUltimateChristmasPresent.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Disney Channel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crumpet and Sparky will be here before you can name the reindeer.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Common sense aside, could you imagine how useful a machine that can control the weather can be? Girl steals weather machine but her misuse ruins her Christmas. But the real entertainment comes from John Salley (&lt;em&gt;Detriot Pistons star&lt;/em&gt;) and Bill Fagerbakke (&lt;em&gt;Patrick from SpongeBob&lt;/em&gt;) as giant elfs. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;high-school-musical-2-2007&quot;&gt;14. High School Musical 2 (2007)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DCOM/14_HighSchoolMusical2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Disney Channel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You know the words “once upon a time”. Make you listen, there’s a reason.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Summer break means summer jobs for East High students at a local country club. More singing, drama than the first. Although the film doesn’t do justice to musicals, it still had a message about fixing mistakes and handling choices that affect your future.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-date-with-the-presidents-daughter-1998&quot;&gt;13. My Date with the President’s Daughter (1998)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DCOM/13_MyDateWithThePresidentsDaughter.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Disney Channel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oh, 1600 Pennsylvania Avenue. It’s a big white house, you can’t miss it.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The story of a magician wannabe (Will Friedle) falling for the daughter of the President of the United States (Elisabeth Harnois) and their wild adventure. I’m guessing it’s not that easy to get away from the Secret Service like they did in the film, but hey, it’s Eric Matthews from &lt;em&gt;Boy Meets World&lt;/em&gt;!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;full-court-miracle-2003&quot;&gt;12. Full Court Miracle (2003)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DCOM/12_FullCourtMiracle.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Disney Channel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t do that. Don’t you put yourselves in a box… ever.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A sports movie about jewish kids who want to succeed in basketball. Yarmulke and all! It told a story on how you can overcome religion barriers yet still stay true to what you believe in.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;luck-of-the-irish-2001&quot;&gt;11. Luck of the Irish (2001)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DCOM/11_LuckOfTheIrish.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Disney Channel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dancing’s not a sport. Ah, it is in Ireland.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Pretty Little Liar star Ryan Merriman stars in a DCOM showcasing the importance of learning where you come from. It taught kids to embrace who they were and learn to put differences aside when family is in the mix. Also I learned a lot about the Irish culture with the film’s olympic style competition.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;eddies-million-dollar-cook-off-2003&quot;&gt;10. Eddie’s Million Dollar Cook-Off (2003)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DCOM/10_EddiesMillionDollarCookoff.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Disney Channel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They’re carrots, whatever you do to them, they’re going to taste like carrots!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A good movie about struggling with approval from your friends and family about doing what you want to do. I’ve always been a fan of Food Network cooking competitions, so seeing a baseball kid make chocolate chicken was pretty cool.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cadet-kelly-2002&quot;&gt;9. Cadet Kelly (2002)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DCOM/09_CadetKelly.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Disney Channel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once a maggot, always a maggot.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Christy Carlson Romano and Hillary Duff come off two very great Disney Channel Series shows &lt;em&gt;(Even Stevens and Lizzie McGuire, respectively)&lt;/em&gt;. Duff’s girly character and Romano’s uptight rule-follower attitude turned out to become one of the most unlikely of friendships. X-men’s Iceman guest stars.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;double-teamed-2002&quot;&gt;8. Double Teamed (2002)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DCOM/08_DoubleTeamed.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Disney Channel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Once second best always second best&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The real-life story of WNBA twin sisters showed the difficulty of sibling rivalries, living up to expectations from parents and coaches, and dealing with not being the number-one option. But those Elvis sandwiches they made in the film. Yum. And I learned that this is the one DCOM where you should beware doing a Google Image search on.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;motocrossed-2001&quot;&gt;7. Motocrossed (2001)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DCOM/07_Motocrossed.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Disney Channel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t be such a girl Carson.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;She’s All That&lt;/em&gt; with a deeper focus on family relationships. A aspiring motorist pretends to be her brother to compete. The film revolved around motorbikes but the true impact of the film was dealing between the choice of your family and winning.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;alley-cats-strike-2000&quot;&gt;6. Alley Cats Strike (2000)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DCOM/06_AlleyCatsStrike.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Disney Channel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wouldn’t you like to know?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
I gained a new interest in bowling. For those who watched the film, I tried that 7-10 split shot where he spun the bowling ball and gave it a slight push. Let’s just say someone needed to walk into the lane because the ball got stuck. And yes, that is a young Kaley Cuoco &lt;em&gt;(Big Bang Theory)&lt;/em&gt;. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;smart-house-1999&quot;&gt;5. Smart House (1999)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DCOM/05_SmartHouse.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Disney Channel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We can’t stay here forever, PAT!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Ryan Merriman is the ultimate tech boy-genius &lt;em&gt;(c’mon he won a house)&lt;/em&gt;. But most importantly, a kitchen counter that magically brings you food? The American dream realized. &lt;em&gt;Smart House&lt;/em&gt; taught kids it is important not to misuse power.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;johnny-tsunami-1999&quot;&gt;4. Johnny Tsunami (1999)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DCOM/04_JohnnyTsunami.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Disney Channel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go Big or Go Home.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Living in Hawaii my entire life, seeing this kid go from Hawaii to Vermont and transitioning from surfing to snowboarding showed how two very different things (ocean waves and mountains of snow) can play the same. A turf war between the preppy skiers and soul-snowboarders leads to a fun story about finding your own greatness. Also I only knew Cary-Hiroyuki Tagawa from Mortal Kombat, but seeing him as the wise and laid back grandpa, right on.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;high-school-musical-2006&quot;&gt;3. High School Musical (2006)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DCOM/03_HighSchoolMusical.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Disney Channel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What team? WILDCATS!&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The grease-like musical that kickstarted a generation of music dancing. This movie introduced Zac Efron and Vanessa Hudgens and helped towards their now successful careers. A basketball who bakes and nerd who break dances speaking out really helped portray the film’s message. Even if you’re not a fan, you can’t deny HSM’s success led to another DCOM and a full-featured film.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;zenon-girl-of-the-21st-century-1999&quot;&gt;2. Zenon: Girl of the 21st Century (1999)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DCOM/02_ZenonGirlofthe21stCentury.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Disney Channel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zoom zoom zoom, you make my heart go boom boom. My super nova girl.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The futuristic camp station, space ships from the earth to the moon, and catchy songs! The film made me want to live in space and hoped the future was here. I mean they predicted information to destroy a space station could fit on miniature CDs.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;brink-1998&quot;&gt;1. Brink (1998)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/images/DCOM/01_Brink.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Disney Channel&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skate better? Skate. Better.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Soul Skating: skateing for the fun of it and not for the money. This was the first DCOM I watched and really got me hooked on the ideas of DCOMs. The story of a teenage skater with raw talent who struggles with his options: soul skating or being a sellout (with assholes) to help his family. In the end, Brink figured it out and told the douche: “But hey, the good guys win. Yeah I wanna win, but at the end of the day, win or lose, I’m still not you… So it’s still a good day.”
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/DCOM-rank/&quot;&gt;Rank 'Em:  Disney Channel Original Movies&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Joshua T. Rivera at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Doswah&lt;/a&gt; on June 25, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lanikai Pillboxes Hike]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/lanikai-pillboxes-hike/" />
  <id>/lanikai-pillboxes-hike</id>
  <updated>2014-06-12 15:04:55 -1000T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2014-06-12T00:00:00-10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Joshua T. Rivera</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>doswah@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently completed the Lanikai Pillbox hike for the first time with Rachel. Here’s to completing more hikes this summer!
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;http://hike2grind.com/?p=44&quot;&gt;Visit my Hike2Grind post to view my experience&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/lanikai-pillboxes-hike/&quot;&gt;Lanikai Pillboxes Hike&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Joshua T. Rivera at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Doswah&lt;/a&gt; on June 12, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Fault In Our Stars: Metaphors and Misery]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/the-fault-in-our-stars/" />
  <id>/the-fault-in-our-stars</id>
  <updated>2014-06-07 23:46:33 -1000T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2014-06-07T00:00:00-10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Joshua T. Rivera</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>doswah@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;!-- Table of Contents
&lt;section id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot; class =&quot;toc&quot;&gt;
  &lt;header&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Contents&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;/header&gt;
&lt;div id=&quot;drawer&quot; markdown=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
*  Auto generated table of contents
{:toc}
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt; 
--&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;image-pull-left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/TFIOS/fault-in-our-stars-poster.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;MoviePoster&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I recently watched the &lt;em&gt;The Fault In Our Stars&lt;/em&gt; with my friends on opening night and I decided to write my reactions. The film stars Shailene Woodley and Ansel Elgort as the teenage duo Hazel Lancaster and Augustus (Gus) Waters. This highly anticipated book-to-film adaptation is a fresh installment that stands out in a plethora of romantic dramas over the years. One thing is for sure, the film’s tagline lives up it’s name. This definitely &lt;em&gt;one sick love story.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning:&lt;/strong&gt; There are spoilers from the film! &lt;em&gt;Do not&lt;/em&gt; read on if you plan to watch the movie without knowing about the story. If you do read on, please share your comments with me at the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;review&quot;&gt;Review&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; read the book and this is purely my reaction of just the film. Here is the storyline from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt2582846/&quot;&gt;IMDB&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hazel and Gus are two teenagers who share an acerbic wit, a disdain for the conventional, and a love that sweeps them on a journey. Their relationship is all the more miraculous given that Hazel has another other constant companion: an oxygen tank, Gus jokes about his prosthetic leg, and they met and fell in love at a cancer support group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;image-pull-left&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/TFIOS/fault-in-our-stars-swingset.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Swingset&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;all-the-feels&quot;&gt;All The Feels&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;image-pull-left&quot;&gt;The film’s main characters: Hazel (Woodley) and Gus (Elgort) have great chemistry and their strong performances allow the viewer to really buy into their emotions and struggles. The character’s attitudes towards life and death is an emotional roller-coaster. Throughout the film, the director maneuvers with a linear and coherent story to capture the heart-warming (&lt;em&gt;and the heart-breaking&lt;/em&gt;) moments of Hazel’s narrative. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I felt there were missing back stories for the main characters that could have helped the film. After discussing with the book-readers, the movie did not accomplish sensitive themes the book did, so I now I have the desire to read the popular book one day. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Back to my missing back story thought. In the unraveling of a romance between a girl living in the moment and a boy living in his dream; the formula: the struggling girl meets the perfect guy does not tackle the film’s heavy themes of the side effects of dying. Why is Augustus the perfect guy from the beginning? But I stopped asking all these questions halfway through the movie because the balance of the film works so well.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The film works with light-hearted and entertaining scenes (&lt;em&gt;the virgin venn diagram XD&lt;/em&gt;). Nonetheless, the moments that hit you were the enlightening character growth: Hazel handling with herself when she meets her favorite author, Hazel’s parents making their future life plans, and Augustus helping his friend Isaac in impactful way.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/TFIOS/dinner.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dinner&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-verdict&quot;&gt;The Verdict&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt; The Fault In Our Stars is an incredibly touching,  well-executed film filled with tearjerking moments thanks to powerful performances and a relentless story with timeless thoughts about love, life, and courage that proves a teenage romantic drama can be a small infinity worth every moment.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I realize why girls “wait” for their Augustus Waters &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Okay? Okay. OMG stop flirting with me!” &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quotes, metaphors, and math theories galore!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;watch-if-you-crave-a-fresh-and-philosophical-romantic-drama-and-maybe-a-tear-here-or-there&quot;&gt;Watch if you crave a fresh and philosophical romantic drama (and maybe a tear here or there).&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;discussion&quot;&gt;Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The film succeeds in capturing my attention through clever quotes and scenes with meaning. I may have a complete understanding, just remember that &lt;strong&gt;I’m just writing how I feel about them&lt;/strong&gt;. There were so many, but here are some of my favorites:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;metaphors&quot;&gt;1. Metaphors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;image-pull-left&quot;&gt;Within the first few scenes, you meet Augustus Waters. Shortly after getting Hazel to watch a movie with him, Gus places a cigarette in his mouth much to Hazel’s disgust. He tells her &lt;em&gt;“It’s a metaphor, see. You put the killing thing right between your teeth but you don’t give it the power to do it’s killing.”&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/TFIOS/metaphor.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Metaphor&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This was a way for Gus to tell himself that he has control over his fate (up to a certain extent). We all have control over our fate to a certain degree. I found this powerful because our attitude toward of life can make the biggest of impacts. Metaphors give us the positive power to things just by looking at something in a creative way. Personally, I keep mementos to remind myself of people and events that changed me and remind me to do good. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;our-little-infinity&quot;&gt;2. Our Little Infinity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later in the film, when Gus summons Hazel and Isaac to a church so he can listen to their eulogies they prepared for him, Hazel recites a touching piece that represented her love for Gus. She highlighted: &lt;em&gt;“Some infinities are bigger than other infinities.”&lt;/em&gt; (there are an infinite amount of numbers (0.1, 0.11, 0.12) between two domains. Whether it is from 0 to 1 or 0 to a million.) The fact is the infinity between 0 and a million is greater than the infinity between  0 to 1. Hazel and Gus’ relationship is time set shorter than other couples, but she &lt;strong&gt;chooses&lt;/strong&gt; to see it as an infinity. She acknowledges that she is thankful Gus gave her “forever” (an infinity) within their number of days, their set.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The sets that can drive us insane &lt;em&gt;(attending a class, being parent, or even growing up)&lt;/em&gt; are a finite amount of hours, days, or years. We can digest their meaning through analogies. Hazel’s analogy helps bring structure to &lt;em&gt;clarify our purpose&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;appraise how we live our life&lt;/em&gt;. I believe value is in the eye of the beholder. Seeing infinities are rare, but it is because there are only a handful of sets that truly clarify ourselves now and who we want to be.  My infinities are the memories are filled with people whom I will always cherish and will never forget. I am fortunate I can always recall these memories since they reflect who I am and bring me peace of mind. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
So. We can choose to wish we have more numbers or we can perceive a set feel like an infinity. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;who-is-august-waters&quot;&gt;3. Who Is August Waters?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;EDIT: I realized I spelt Augustus as August I elected not to change it because I thought it was funny.&lt;/em&gt; My friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://jordynchung.tumblr.com&quot;&gt;Jordyn&lt;/a&gt; shared this post with me from her Tumblr:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There are 313 pages… We don’t meet Augustus until page 8… He does not speak until page 11… He leaves us on page 261… That is 253 pages from when we meet him until he leaves… And within those 253 pages… He is physically in 172 of them… And that is all it took. 172 pages for us to fall in love with Augustus Waters. And none of us will be the same again…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Considering I read this before watching the film. I thought to myself: &lt;em&gt;what is the deal with this guy?&lt;/em&gt; Is he the &lt;em&gt;perfect&lt;/em&gt; man? Well not exactly. After watching the film, he was the personification of passion. His relentless full-court press attempts for Hazel’s heart was an instinct of his principles. He is understands where he stands in this world and he shapes himself on his own terms. I see him as someone who is truly happy because of decisions bring him some kind of peace. Augusts is a survivor and applies the ideas of heroism and courage from his video games to his life. Generally people adore heroes and feed from courage. With that notion, he became fixated with timeless legacy. But in his last scenes, Hazel comforts him that her care should be enough. Showing him and all of us, there’s contentment with being in love with a single person. Contentment is difficult to overcome everyday because of our human desire to be better than people or ourselves. Which the movie speaks to me: we need someone to remind us that we are loved because anyone can be easily consumed by themselves.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Augusts’ character uncovered that such great heights are fulfilling. Unfortunately they involve persistent courage and an outrageous amount of thought, hence, why Augusts Waters is a character in a book. Though fictional, anyone can collect what made him inspiration to living a quality way to live our lives.&lt;/p&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/the-fault-in-our-stars/&quot;&gt;The Fault In Our Stars: Metaphors and Misery&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Joshua T. Rivera at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Doswah&lt;/a&gt; on June 07, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Updating a Jekyll Blog on Webfaction]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/updating-a-jekyll-blog-on-webfaction/" />
  <id>/updating-a-jekyll-blog-on-webfaction</id>
  <updated>2014-06-02 12:26:59 -1000T00:00:00-00:00</updated>
  <published>2014-06-02T00:00:00-10:00</published>
  
  <author>
    <name>Joshua T. Rivera</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>doswah@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After assembling &lt;a href=&quot;http://joshuatrivera.com&quot;&gt;joshuatrivera.com&lt;/a&gt; I figured it would be a good idea to figure out the best way to operate a blogging site using a git hook like in my &lt;a href=&quot;http://doswha.com/git-hook-static-websites&quot;&gt;earlier post&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
After several searches I discovered Jekyll was a great option when it comes to creative website control, because &lt;em&gt;everyone&lt;/em&gt; likes control. Since I host on WebFaction, I needed a smart way to deploy a Jekyll Blog. After hours of scratching my head, I stubmled upon this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.garron.me/en/blog/host-your-jekyll-blog-on-webfaction.html&quot;&gt;tutorial from Guillermo Garron&lt;/a&gt;. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Essentially this process is to generate my site locally then rsync to a static-only site created on WebFaction. I performed the following instruction to install the software on the WebFaction servers by installing the gems and updating the path through the bashrc file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;notice&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important!&lt;/strong&gt; In the tutorial, it is not mentioned to install the ‘therubyracer’ gem. But you do need to install it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;$ export GEM_HOME=$HOME/gems
$ source ./bashrc
$ gem2.0 install jekyll
$ gem2.0 install RedCloth
$ gem2.0 install therubyracer
$ export PATH=$HOME/gems/bin:$PATH
$ source .bashrc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next I set up a bare git repository where we will put our git hook as seen here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;$ cd webapps/git/repos/
$ mkdir doswah.git
$ cd doswah.git
$ git init bare&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, I created a ‘post-update’ file in the hooks folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;$ cd hooks
$ vi post-update&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should have these following lines. For your specific project you will need to edit line 3 and change the path of ‘REPOSITORY_DIR’ to your project .git folder you just created. On line 12, you must edit the last path to where your web application is. In my case, it is in the ‘webapps’ folder. In all other instances you see ‘doswah’ change it to your username.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 1&lt;/span&gt; #!/bin/bash
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 2&lt;/span&gt; # Declare variables
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 3&lt;/span&gt; REPOSITORY_DIR=&amp;quot;/home/doswah/git/repos/doswah.git&amp;quot;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 4&lt;/span&gt; DEPLOY_FIR=&amp;quot;/home/doswah/tmp/jekyll-tmp&amp;quot;
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 5&lt;/span&gt; DEPLOY_TMP_DIR=$(mktemp /home/doswah/tmp/jekyll.deploy.XXXXX)
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 6&lt;/span&gt; rm -f $DEPLOY_TMP_DIR
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 7&lt;/span&gt; git clone $REPOSITORY_DIR $DEPLOY_TMP_DIR
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 8&lt;/span&gt; cd $DEPLOY_TMP_DIR
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt; 9&lt;/span&gt; jekyll build -d $DEPLOY_DIR
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;10&lt;/span&gt; rm -rf $DEPLOY_TMP_DIR
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;11&lt;/span&gt; cd /
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;12&lt;/span&gt; rsync -vrz -checksum -e ssh -delete $DEPLOY_DIR /home/doswah/webapps/doswah&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that is done. You can create your git remote on your machine locally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;$ git remote add webfaction doswah@web351.webfaction.com:/home/doswah/git/repos/doswah.git
$ git push doswah&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/updating-a-jekyll-blog-on-webfaction/&quot;&gt;Updating a Jekyll Blog on Webfaction&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Joshua T. Rivera at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Doswah&lt;/a&gt; on June 02, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using a Git Hook for Deploying Static Websites]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/git-hook-static-websites/" />
  <id>/git-hook-static-websites</id>
  <published>2014-05-09T00:00:00-10:00</published>
  <updated>2014-05-09T00:00:00-10:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Joshua T. Rivera</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>doswah@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.kennyluong.com&quot;&gt;Kenny&lt;/a&gt; tell me about his ability to make local edits to his personal websites and remotely push his changes to his Webfaction server through git, I thought I would give it a try for my &lt;a href=&quot;http://joshuatrivera.com&quot;&gt;personal website&lt;/a&gt;. With help from &lt;a href=&quot;http://toroid.org/ams/git-website-howto&quot;&gt;Totoid&lt;/a&gt;, I was able to implement this time-saving tool to make git pushes into a remote repository with a detached work tree where a &lt;i&gt;post-receive&lt;/i&gt; hook runs a &lt;code&gt;git checkout -f&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;setup-on-your-local-computer&quot;&gt;Setup On Your Local Computer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I created a local respository titled &lt;code&gt;joshuatrivera&lt;/code&gt; and initalized a git repository with a &lt;code&gt;index.html&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;$ mkdir joshuatrivera 
$ cd joshuatrivera
$ git init
$ echo &amp;quot;Hello, world!&amp;quot; &amp;gt; index.html
$ git add index.html
$ git commit -m &amp;quot;First commit&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;performing-the-web-host-setup&quot;&gt;Performing the Web Host Setup&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In webfaction, I needed to create two applications: a git app and a app to hold my website source code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;setting-up-applications-in-webfaction&quot;&gt;1. Setting Up Applications In WebFaction&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under applications I created an Application named &lt;code&gt;Git&lt;/code&gt; with the App Category &lt;code&gt;Git&lt;/code&gt; and App type set to the default &lt;code&gt;Git 1.7.4.1&lt;/code&gt;. Next I create an Application for my personal website &lt;code&gt;joshuatrivera&lt;/code&gt; with the App Category set to &lt;code&gt;PHP&lt;/code&gt; and App type to the default &lt;code&gt;Static/CGI/PHP-5.5&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;creating-the-post-receive-hook-in-the-git-app&quot;&gt;2. Creating The post-receive Hook In The Git App&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I ssh into my WebFaction and visit the &lt;code&gt;webapps&lt;/code&gt; folder,  I see the two applications I created &lt;code&gt;Git&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;joshuatrivera&lt;/code&gt;. Then I created a bare .git folder within the git app to generate the post-receive files used to update files in &lt;code&gt;joshuatrivera&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;$ cd git/repos
$ mkdir joshuatrivera.git 
$ cd joshuatrivera.git
$ git init --bare&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This creates the necessary files and folders for our git setup. Inside the &lt;code&gt;joshuatrivera.git&lt;/code&gt; folder we just created, there is a &lt;code&gt;hooks&lt;/code&gt; folder where you will create a file named &lt;code&gt;post-receive&lt;/code&gt; where the scripts will go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;$ cd hooks
$ vi post-receive&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I added these lines in the &lt;code&gt;post-receive&lt;/code&gt; file I just created and opened&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; #!/bin/sh
&lt;span class=&quot;lineno&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt; GIT_WORK_TREE=/path/to/webapp git checkout -f master&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my case, &lt;code&gt;path/to/webapp&lt;/code&gt; for me was &lt;code&gt;/home/doswah/webapps/joshuatrivera&lt;/code&gt;. Then I needed to provide the necessary permissions so the post-receive script can write to the appropriate file. So after creating the &lt;code&gt;post-receive&lt;/code&gt; file, type&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;$ chmod +x post-receive&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;connect-to-post-receive-file-through-ssh&quot;&gt;Connect To Post-Receive File Through SSH&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that setup in our WebFaction setup, now we need to create the functionality I wanted on my local machine. I created a remote to the .git repository I made in WebFaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;$ git remote add joshuatrivera ssh://&lt;span class=&quot;nt&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;webfaction_login&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;/home/doswah/webapps/git/repos/joshuatrivera.git
$ git push joshuatrivera +master:refs/heads/master&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my case, my &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;webfaction_login&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; is &lt;code&gt;doswah@web351.webfaction.com&lt;/code&gt; . Now the files I push through the git push command will appear in the &lt;code&gt;joshuatrivera&lt;/code&gt; application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;updating-my-website&quot;&gt;Updating My Website&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally. Now when I make changes on my local machine, to update this to the WebFaction server I can just run&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;$ git push joshuatrivera&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This transfers any pushed commits from my local repository where the &lt;code&gt;post-receive&lt;/code&gt; hook will update &lt;code&gt;joshuatrivera&lt;/code&gt; for me!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;github-setup&quot;&gt;GitHub Setup&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then setup a GitHub repository then added a remote. Since I created a commit already, I made a commit to the master.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot; data-lang=&quot;html&quot;&gt;$ git remote add origin git@github.com:Doswah/joshuatrivera.com.git
$ git push -u origin master&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/git-hook-static-websites/&quot;&gt;Using a Git Hook for Deploying Static Websites&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Joshua T. Rivera at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Doswah&lt;/a&gt; on May 09, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>
